Okay, today we are going to be talking about some different linear models in time series analysis.
And I've cleverly labeled this cryptically with ARMA models.
You may not know what that is right now, but by the end of today you certainly will.
Topics for today, we're going to start out by reviewing white noise and random walks.
Remember, those were really simple time series models.
And then we'll start talking about some somewhat more interesting time series models, autoregressive, moving average, the combination of those two autoregressive moving averages.
And then we're going to revisit the autocorrelation function and partial autocorrelation function and see how those can be used to identify the orders of AR or MA models.
Okay, so recall from last Thursday that a white noise is a time series where all of its values are independent, and they're identically distributed with a mean of zero.
And we talked about how that distributional form for the errors is flexible, right?
So here was an example where we were flipping a coin and taking twice that value subtracting one.
And so we had a time series that was just bouncing back and forth between minus one and one, the mean was zero, and there is no correlation over time.
You can see that the autocorrelation function is one at zero, because it's correlated with itself, and it's essentially functionally at zero everywhere else.